American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIj. 1898-1984 APS.Archives.IIj APS.Archives.IIj
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to J. Minus [sic, Isaac Minis] Hays, March 28, 1898; 10x8; Wahl, William H. (William Henry), 1848-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns order for Franklin Institute publication.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], March 28, 1898; 8x5; Willcox, Joseph, 1829?-1918
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns paper(on APS copy of Declaration of Independence?) Refers to F.J. Dreer.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 29, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Bryn Mawr College. Library
    Bryn Mawr, Pa., A.L.S.: Jane B. Haines 2p., end. Asks to consult certain series.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 29, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Phila, A.L.S. 4p. Concerns publication of paper on beavers in Transactions. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol.19, pp. 417-139.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 29, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Willcox, Joseph, 1829?-1918
    Phila., A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Will meet committee (on APS copy of Declaration of Independence?)
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 30, 1898; 6-1/2x8-1/2; Douglas, James, 1837-1918
    Typed L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Sends obituary of T.S. Hunt.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 30, 1898; 8x5; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Nominates Henry Grier Bryant as member.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, March 31, 1898; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Nominates Lamar Gray Patterson for membership. DuBois and Prime will sign the nomination paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 31, 1898; 8x5, 9-1/4x6; North, Edward, 1820-1903
    Clinton, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Enc. of 2p. printed sheet Concerns death of I.H. Hall. Sends copy of his obituary. Refers to his nomination of A.H. Chester for membership.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, March 31, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. About paper on beavers for Transactions. Refers to Harrison Allen's plates. For printed paper on beavers, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439. For Allen paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 237-272.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 1, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Green, E. L.
  - Letter to MacCalla and Co., April 1, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Los Angeles Public Library
    Los Angeles, Cal., Typed L.S.: Harriet Child Wadleigh 1p. Asks about purchase of A.P.S. publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 2, 1898; 10-1/2x8, 13-1/4x8-1/4; Franklin Institute (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illia]m H[enry] Wahl, with stamp 1p. Enc. of 1p. typed list Sends list of societies with which Institute exchanges publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 2, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting. Returns corrected proofs.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 2, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Montgomery, Thomas Lynch, 1862-
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Will attend meeting.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 2, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns corrected proofs and asks about separates. For printed papers, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 273-324, 325-415.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, April 2, 1898; 4-1/2x8-1/2; Stockhausen, P.C., co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Encs. wanting. Sends proofs of plates.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 3, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 1p. Will send additional MS. for his paper.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], April 4, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 2p. Encs. wanting. Returns corrected proofs.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 4, 1898; 9-1/2x6; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., L. 2p. Concerns number of copies of Proceedings which were mailed out.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 4, 1898; 8x5; North, Edward, 1820-1903
    Clinton, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his nomination of A.H. Chester for membership.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 6, 1898; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Favaro, Antonio, 1847-1922
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for loan of issue of Bulletin of the Engineers Club of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 6, 1898; 11x8-1/2; University of Illinois (Urbana-Champaign campus). Library
    Urbana, Ill., Typed L.S.: Katharine L. Sharp 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 7, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Lester, Levant Delos
    Buffalo, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 8, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Campbell, James S.
    Pittsburg, Pa., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 8, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Lancaster County Historical Society (Pa.)
    Lancaster, Pa., A.L.S.: S. M. Sener 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 9, 1898; 11x8-1/2; May, Joseph
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for early documents of First Unitarian Church of Philadelphia, left at A.P.S. by John Vaughan.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] M[inis] Hays, April 11, 1898; 11x8-1/2; The associated news
    New York Typed L.S.: Harold Cook, Editor 1p. Asks for copy of Hays's paper on A.P.S. copy of Declaration of Independence. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol.37, pp. 88-107.
  - Letter to J. Minnis [sic, Isaac Minis] Hays, April 11, 1898; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns publications for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 11, 1898; 10-1/2x8-1/2; See, T. J. J. (Thomas Jefferson Jackson), b. 1866
    Flagstaff, Ariz., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns proofs of paper on stellar systems. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 221-235.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 11, 1898; 9x6; Wilder, Burt G. (Burt Green), 1841-1925
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Asks for assistance on compiling Harrison Allen bibliography.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 11, March 11, 1898; 8x5; Janney, John Jay, 1812-1907
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerns spelling in Jefferson draft of Declaration of Independence.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 12, 1898; 9x5-1/2; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., L. 2p. Concerns size of bill for Proceedings and the separates for Brinton, Field and Prime.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 13, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Presents copy of catalog of F. Peale's collection of Stone Age relics.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, April 13, 1898; 11x8-1/2, 3-1/2x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and envelope Will present catalogue of Peale Stone Age collection to A.P.S. Refers to F. Fraley.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 14, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Drake, N. F. (Noah Fields), b. 1864
    Tsientsin, China, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns paper on coal fields of the Indian Territory. Refers to Branner.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 14, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Prince, John Dyneley, 1868-1945
    N[ew] Y[ork] Typed L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Thanks for separates of paper on Passamaquoddy wampum. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 479-495.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 14, 1898; 8-1/4x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Presents portraits of Fraley and J.P. Lesley, by M.L. Bush Brown. Encloses list of subscribers.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 14, 1898; 8x5-1/4; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Fraley portrait.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 15, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Ford, Paul Leicester, 1865-1902
    Brooklyn, N.Y., Typed L.S.,with MS. corrections 1p. Arranges to consult Franklin material.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 15, 1898; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends letter from Robert Patterson. For enclosure, see Patterson to Fraley, Nov. 30, 1898.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 15, 1898; 9x6; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Beaver, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his paper on beavers. Refers to Harrison Allen's plates. For beaver paper, see:APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439. For Allen paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 237-272.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 16, 1898; 11-1/4x8-1/4; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Copenhagen, L.S.: H[ieronymus] G[eorg] Zeuthen 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 16, 1898; 8x5; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Concerns printing of and voting on the revised laws.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 16, 1898; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Sends Report for 1853.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hayes [sic], April 18, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., L.S. with stamp 1p., end. Asks for meeting of committee on W.T. Hewett's paper.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 18, 1898; 8x5; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Question of re-publication [of By-Laws?]
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 18, 1898; 5-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for Library Committee meeting.
  - Memorandum to I. Minis Hays, April 18, 1898; 11x8-1/4; May, Joseph
    A.D.S. 1p. Wishes the J.Vaughan material pertaining to the Unitarian church which is to be turned over to them.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, April 18, 1898; 10x8; Thomson, John, 1835-1916
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns union list of periodicals for Philadelphia area.
  - Letter to Ella Moreson [sic, Morison], April 19, 1898; 11x8; Engineers Club of Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Sends publication for use by A.N. Favaro.
  - Letter to J. Minnis [sic, Isaac Minis] Hays, April 19, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Sends requested documents for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 19, 1898; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning W.T. Hewett's paper on Goethe. Refers to J.P. Lesley portrait.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, April 19, 1898; 8x5; Tower, Charlemagne, 1848-1923
    Vienna, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns exchange of publications with Austro-Hungarian learned societies. Compliments Hays on paper on APS copy of Declaration of Independence. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 88-107.
  - Letter to Miss Morrison [sic, Ella M. Morison], April 21, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Atlantic City, N.J., A.L. on postal card S. 1p., end., and add. Requests names of A.P.S. officers and members.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 21, 1898; 5-1/2x8-1/2; First Congregational Society of Unitarian Christians in the City of Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Jo[h]n P. Croasdale (?) 1p. Thanks for gift of papers of church. Refers to Joseph May.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, April 22, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Hopes to send publications for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] M[inis] Hays, April 22, 1898; 3x5-1/2; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L. on postal card, filled in in MS. 1p. and add. Concerns supplement to Scudder's Nomenclator zoologicus.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, April 22, 1898; 10-1/2x8; United States. Hydrographic Office
    Washington, Typed L.S.: J[oseph] E[dgar] Craig 1p. Concerns copy of American practical navigator by Bowditch for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, April 23, 1898.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 23, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Ford, Paul Leicester, 1865-1902
    Brooklyn, N.Y., Typed L.S. 1p. Arranges to consult Franklin material.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], April 23, 1898; 9x6; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Atlantic City, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about nomination of L.G. Patterson. Refers to F. Fraley, Peale Catalogue of Stone Age Relics.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 25, 1898; 10-1/2x8-1/2; See, T. J. J. (Thomas Jefferson Jackson), b. 1866
    Flagstaff, Ariz., A.L.S. 1p. Has returned proofs of paper of stellar systems. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 221-235.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, April 27, 1898; 11x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Sending copy of report of Venezuelan Boundary Commission for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, April 28, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Cushing, Harry Alonzo, 1870-1955
    [New York], A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about Lee Papers.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], April 28, 1898; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Kroeger, Alice Bertha, d. 1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Apologizes for missing meeting [of Committee on Historical Manuscripts?]
  - Letter to I[saac] Minnis [sic, Minis] Hays, April 28, 1898; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington [D.C.] Typed L.S. with stamp: Andrew H[ussey] Allen 1p. Will help if possible. Refers to G.F. Edmunds.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 29, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. May not attend meeting tomorrow.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 29, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Add James P. Townsend to subscribers to J.P. Lesley and F. Fraley portraits.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 30, 1898; 11-1/4x9; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, A.L.S.: Karl Mayer 1p. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, May 3, 1898; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Cannot secure copied of Revised Statutes and Statutes at Large for A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 3, 1898; 9x6; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Beaver, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Asks about paper on beavers. Will send set of Harrison Allen's papers to Oldfield Thomas at British Museum. For paper on beavers, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 4, 1898; 10-3/4x8; Lacoe, Ralph Dupuy, 1824-1901
    Pittston, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks about papers by Cope on Devonian carboniferous fish. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings, Vol. 36, pp. 71-91.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 5, 1898; 8-1/2x5-3/4, 3-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. of postal card announcing meeting Change of address. Encloses card wrongly addressed.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 5, 1898; 6x8; Douglas, James, 1837-1918
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Submits biblio. of T.S. Hunt's work.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 6, 1898; 10-3/4x8; Lacoe, Ralph Dupuy, 1824-1901
    Pittston, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Orders paper by Cope.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 7, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Ford, Paul Leicester, 1865-1902
    Brooklyn, N.Y., Typed L. 1p. Concerns appointment to see Franklin material.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 7, 1898; 9x6; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Beaver, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns plates for paper on beavers. Refers to J.F. Sachse. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], May 9, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Brown, Arthur Erwin, b. 1850
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 2p. Concerns S.N. Rhoads' paper on beavers. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 9, 1898; 9-3/4x5-3/4; Jayne, Horace, 1859-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns S.N. Rhoads' paper. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], May 9, 1898; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Kroeger, Alice Bertha, d. 1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks to bring in her class.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], May 9, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Sadtler, Samuel P. (Samuel Philip), 1847-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Returns J.C. Morris's remarks with his vote.
  - Letter to W[illiam] B[erryman] Scott, May 9, 1898; 11-1/2x9; Werner & Winter
    Frankfurt a/M., L. 1p. Concerns plates for his papers in APS Transactions. For printed papers, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 273-324, 325-415.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, May 16, 1898; 6x8; Douglas, James, 1837-1918
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns proofs of his obituary of T.S. Hunt.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], May 16, 1898; 9x6; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Atlantic City, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about nomination of L.G. Patterson.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, May 16, 1898; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Sending Report on the destruction of the battleship Maine and a list of books relating to Cuba, for the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to Rich[ard] A[lsop] Cleemann, May 17, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Buti, Rudolph
    Baltimore, Md., A.L.S. 3p. Asks about publication of his paper on fragment of the "Book of the dead." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 38, pp. 79-81.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, May 17, 1898; 10x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Sending copy of Vol. 6 of the Official Records of the Union and Confederate Navies for the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 18, 1898; 8-1/2x5-3/4; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Calls committee meetings. Refers to Hewett.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, May 18, 1898; 6x8; Douglas, James, 1837-1918
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns proofs of obituary of T.S. Hunt.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, May 18, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    Typed L. 1p., end. by Sadtler and Frazer Copy Concerns revision of A.P.S. laws.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 18, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns nominations of E.P. Crowell and W.A. Knight.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 18, 1898; 9x5-1/2; Meehan, Thomas, 1826-1901
    Germantown [Pa.] A.L.S. 1p. Found few publications on list worth exchanging.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 18, 1898; 9x6; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Atlantic City, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for information on election of L.G. Patterson.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 18, Sept. 14, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    A.L.S. on postal card 2 items 2p. and 2 add. Change of address.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 19, 1898; 11x8-1/2; F. A. Davis Company
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Asks to use illustrations for R.S. Culin's [sic, F.H. Cushing's] report on Pepper-Hearst expedition. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 35, pp.329-448.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 20, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Cushing, Harry Alonzo, 1870-1955
    [New York], A.L.S. 1p. Asks to see Lee Papers.
  - Letter to [Frederick Fraley], May 20, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Field Museum of Natural History
    Chicago, Typed L.S.: F[rederick] J. V. Skiff, Director 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 20, 1898; 11x8-1/4; Kearful, Frank J.
    Oklahoma City, Okla., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 20, 1898; 9x6; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., L. 2p. Enc. wanting Sends duplicate proofs of W.B. Scott's paper. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 73-81.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 20, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends letter from Werner & Winter about plates for papers in Transactions. For printed papers, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 273-324, 325-415. For enclosure, see Werner & Winter to W.B. Scott, May 9, 1898.
  - Note to the [American philosophical society], May 21, 1898; 4x5-1/2; Favaro, Antonio, 1847-1922
    Pauda, A.N. 1p., end. Thanks (for use of publication of Engineers' Club of Philadelphia).
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 21, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Ford, Paul Leicester, 1865-1902
    Brooklyn, N.Y., Typed L.S. 1p. Sends bibliographies. Arrangement for pictures for Franklin article.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, May 21, 1898; 10x8; United States. Bureau of the Mint
    Washington, L.S.: B. F. Butler, Acting Director 1p. Requested copy of report on production of precious metals has been sent to A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to I. M. Hays, May 25, 1898.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 22, 1898; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns manuscripts in A.P.S. collections possibly printed in Samuel Hazard's publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, May 23, 1898; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Beiträge zur Geschichte der Nationalökonomie
    Bern, A.L.S.: A. Oncken, on postal card 1p.,end., and add. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays; New York, May 24, 1898; 8x5; De Lancey, Edward F. (Edward Floyd), 1821-1905.
    A.L.S. 2p., end. Asks requirements of membership.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 24, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Ford, Paul Leicester, 1865-1902
    Brooklyn, N.Y., Typed L. 1p. Acknowledges letter of thanks from A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 24, 1898; 4-1/2x8-1/2; Stockhausen, P.C., co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Concerns cost of plates.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 25, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Pettit, Henry, 1842-1921
    Overbrook [Pa.] A.L.S. 3p. Concerns resignation from Committee on Administration and Rules.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], May 27, 1898; 9x5-3/4; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Phillips prize circular.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 28, 1898; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Friedr. Vieweg & Sohn (Firm)
    Braunschweig, L. on postal card 1p., and add. In German Concerns exchanges with Archiv für anthropologie.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 29, 1898; 9-1/2x6; MacCalla & co., inc.
    Phila., L.S.: W[illia]m A. Pickell 2p. Enc. wanting Sends revised proofs of A.P.S. laws. For printed laws, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 155-161.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 30, 1898; 8-1/2x5-3/4; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns meetings of committees on publications and on Hewett's paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 30, 1898; 6x8; Douglas, W.
    Spuyten Duyvil, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns husband's obituary of T.S. Hunt.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 30, 1898; 10-3/4x8-1/4; École française d'Athènes
    Athens, L.S.: E. Mourdy 1p. In French Cannot exchange publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 30, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks to see proofs of reprinted laws and regulations.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, June 1, 1898; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns offer of Mrs. Britton to arrange the Muhlenberg Collection on deposit at Academy of Natural Sciences. Refers to S.G. Dixon, S. Brown.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 1, 1898; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921